Oishi Mahmud

Professional Profile

A dedicated, hardworking Computer Science graduate with working experience in the software industry field. While doing service in industries, I have developed an interest in Computer Graphics, Animation, Natural Language Processing, Artificial Intelligence and want to work to improve people's quality of life by exploring new and challenging ideas.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Master in Information Technology

(Sep 2017 - Dec 2018)

- University of Dhaka, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- CGPA: 3.70 on scale of 4.00
- Thesis: Predicting an Effective Android Application Release Based on User Reviews and Ratings

B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering

(April 2012 - April 2016)

- Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- CGPA: 3.66 on scale of 4.0
- Project: Online Restaurant and Food Enquiry System

Research Experience

Worked on designing classification model to predict effective android application release based on user reviews and ratings.

Supervisor: Assistant Professor Md Saeed Siddik

Professional Experience

Software Eng. II in Test at Infolytx Bangladesh Limited (Aug 2021 - present)

- Make well-structured test cases by analyzing requirements and automate them
- Scrape data from websites and organize them in differently formatted files using automation tool
- Performing non-functional tests (e.g security test, load test, performance test)

SQA Engineer at BitMascot

(Dec 2020 - Aug 2021)

- Analyze requirements and make well-structured test cases
- Perform functional, regression tests on features like concurrency, automatic billing system
- Document system features in the Confluence

SQA Engineer at Technology and Business Solutions Ltd. (Sep 2019 - Sep 2020)

- Perform tests in systems and report bugs in bug tracking systems e.g. JIRA
- Writing automation scripts for a large amount of data input

PUBLICATIONS

Journal

J1. Md. Abdur Rahman, Oishi Mahmud, Nishat Tasnim Niloy, Md. Saeed Siddik,, "Prioritize Android App Reviews for Effective Version Release", ASM Sc. J., Vol. 13, Special Issue 2, 2020 for ICSCC2019.[Paper]

Conference Paper

C1. **Oishi Mahmud**, Nishat Tasnim Niloy, Md. Abdur Rahman, Md. Saeed Siddik, "Predicting an Effective Android Application Release Based on User Reviews and Ratings", 2019 7th International Conference on Smart Computing & Communications (ICSCC), Curtin University, Miri, Sarawak, Malaysia, June 28-30, 2019 [Paper]

LANGUAGE

• Overall score 7 (L: 8, R: 6.5, W: 6, S: 7) in IELTS Academic

SKILLS

- \bullet Programming Language and Application Framework: C, C++, C#, Java, ASP. NET, ASP. NET MVC
- Website Development and Design: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Data Mining and Web Crawling Tools: Weka, Jsoup Parser, Scrapy
- Automation Frameworks and API: Selenium WebDriver, Cypress, Playwright, Postman
- Graphics: Adobe Photoshop , Adobe Illustrator, OpenGL